Finding Aid for the Photographers' Collection LSC.0098
UCLA Library Special Collections
Photographers' collection
1863
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0098
3.0 linear feet (6 boxes and 125 oversize boxes)
Collection consists of original photographs and negatives of various 19th and 20th century photographers covering a broad range of subjects and includes portraits, landscapes, panoramic views, cityscapes and buildings from various geographic locations and photographs from various historical periods.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
PORTIONS OF THIS COLLECTION HAVE BEEN DIGITIZED. See the Online Items Availabble note for the link to the digitized materials.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335833606533
History
The collection contains photographs from the 19th and 20th century covering a broad range of subjects from various geographical locations and historical periods.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of original photographs and negatives of various 19th and 20th century photographers including, Berenice Abbott, Ansel Adams, Felix Bonfils, Paul Caponigro, Imogen Cunningham, Ralph Dalton Cornell, Louis Fleckenstein, William Henry Jackson, George Wharton James, Charles Fletcher Lummis, Julia Margaret Cameron, Burton Frasher, Burton Holmes, Eadweard Muybridge, Barbara Brooks Morgan, Eliot Porter, Marilyn Sanders, Napoleon Sarony, I West Taber, James Van der Zee, Carl Van Vechten, Carlton Watkins, Henry Hebard West, Brett Weston, Edward Weston, and Garry Winogrand. Contains photographs covering a broad range of subjects and includes portraits, landscapes, panoramic views, cityscapes and buildings from various geographic locations and photographs from various historical periods.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by photographer.
Related Material
Picture Collection (Collection 99). Available at Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Photographers Collection (9 items).
Panoramic photographs.; Cityscape photographs.; Portrait photographs.; Landscape photographs.; Photographers -- Archives.; Photographs -- 20th century.; Photographs -- 19th century.
- Shelflist
  General note
  Description derived from in-house card files.
  - Abbott, Bernice: Views of New York and vicinity. v.p., 1935-1938.; 139 items. 20 x 25 cm. Original photographs. (Box 108)
    Visible file of the photos is available.
  - Adams, Ansel Easton, 34 items. 34 photographs. (Box 39)
    Scope and Contents note
    [View of Dickson Plaza, toward Royce Hall.]
  - Adamson, Robert and David Octavius Hill: Drs. Brown & Forbes, Glasgow. [Edinburgh? ***, 184-]; 1 item. 27.5 x 22 cm. Original calotype. Mounted, 55 x 39 cm.
  - Alberts, Ulvis, 1 item. Photograph. (Box 40)
  - Alinari, Giuseppe, 15 items. Photographs. (Box 41)
  - Anderson, James, 4 items. Photographs. (Box 42)
  - Anderson, P. Douglas ***, 2 items. Photographs. (Box 42)
    - A Humbolt Country Ranch, # 15; 9½ x 11½ ins.: 24 x 29 cm.; Silver print; Watermarks on matt, upper left corner; mounted and overmatted: 40.3 x 50.5 cm.
    - Wanderers from Home, # 16; 11½ x 9½ ins.: 29 x 24 cm.; Silver print; Watermarks on matt; mounted and overmatted: 50.4 x 40.5 cm.
  - Annan, James Craig: Sir Francis Grant, P.R.A. New York, *, 1912.; 1 item. 20.7 x 14.8cm. Photogravure. Mounted and overmatted: 40.5 x 33cm. (Box 26)
    Made from David Octavius Hill's original paper negative, 1846.
    Removed from Camera Work, Vol. 37, January 1912. (*TR/C15)
  - Baker, Viroque: Portrait of Ernest M. Pratt. [Los Angeles (Calif.), ca. 1929-1932]; 1 item. 23.6 x 18.3cm. Photograph. Mounted 27.9 x 23.6cm. (Box 43)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Viroque Baker and Ernest Pratt were local Los Angeles commercial photographers and California Pictorialists. They worked together in the 1920s-30s.
  - Baker, Viroque: View of an unidentified neo-Spanish two-storey house., undated; 1 item. 24.9 x 19.7 cm. Photograph. (Box 43)
  - Baldus, Edouard: Views of Paris.*, ca. 1867.; 4 items. Photographs. (Box 34)
    1. Panthéon, 27 x 21cm.
    2. Fontaine des innocents, 21 x 26 cm.
    3. La Tour St. Jacques, 45 x 33 cm. and 28 x 18 cm.
  - Beato, Antonio ***, 6 items. Photographs.
    Antonio Beato, probably the brother of Felice Beato, is best known for his photographs of the Near East. Until recently, it was thought that Felice and Antonio were one and the same person. In fact, Lee. D. Witken, in his book, The Photograph Collector's Guide, attributes Antonio's work to Felice, calling him Felice A. Beato. Paul Cheveddon's research on Antonio Beato and a recent work on Felice Beato by Pierre Loti entitled, Once Upon a Time: Visions of Old Japan, have now firmly established that Antonio and Felice were two separate people, probably brothers.
    Antonio is thought to have worked in India with Felice Beato and James Robertson for the firm Robertson & Beato, and that might be where the confusion starts. Also, Felice Beato and James Robertson had been in Egypt in the late 1850s and had photographed travel scenes there as well. However, for the most part, their photographs were not signed.
    Antonio Beato arrived in Egypt in approximately 1862 and set up a studio in Luxor, where he had a relatively flourishing business, lasting until ca. 1890s. Not much else is known about him, however, other than the fact that he was the photographer for the William Vanderbilt party tour of the Nile. The two albums which came out of this tour are part of the holdings of the Department of Special Collections.
    The photographs which comprise this collection are all of the Nile River valley. They are albumen prints, mounted and overmatted, and identified on the verso in pencil. In addition, Beato's own negative number is also supplied on the verso of each print. All are part of a purchase from Steven Lieber, 1986. These photographs augment a good collection of albums and individual photographs from this time period in the Middle East already in the Department of Special Collections.
    - Assouan Hotel, # 59?; 20 x 26 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      Close-up view of Assouan Hotel.
      See also negatives #45, 535.
    - Assouan vue prise de l'ile elephantine, # 536; 26 x35 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      View of Aswan from Elephantine Island.
    - Dahubieh qui invute le Nil, # 586; 26 x 36 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      Close-up view of riverboat on the Nile.
    - Vue d'assouan, # 535; 26 x 35 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      Same image as negative #45: closer view.
    - Vue d'assouan, # 45; 20 x 26 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      River bank scene from summit; boats in water, town in the distance.
    - Vue d'asyiut, # 366; 20 x 26 cm.; mounted: 41 x 51 cm.
      Man and palm trees at river bank; signature in the negative, "A. Beato," reversed.
  - Beato, Antonio ***, 15 items. Photographs.
    There is only sketchy knowledge of Felice (also known as Felix) Beato's early career prior to his settling in Japan. It is thought that he was probably Venetian by birth and later became a naturalized British citizen, but when this occurred is not clear. It is certain that he worked as a photographer in 1850 in Malta and that is where he teamed up with the English photographer, James Robertson. In approximately 1852, they created a partnership called Robertson & Beato. At this time, they photographed in calotype. By the time they set out to photograph the Crimean War in 1856, they had switched to the wet collodian process. After the Crimean War, where they had replaced BritiSh photographer, Roger Fenton, the two then traveled to Greece and the Middle East to photograph travel scenes.
    The British Government then sent them to India to document the Bengal Sepoy Mutiny. Beato's photographs taken in Lucknow were the first ever to record actual corpses. Until then, proper Victorian taste as to war images ran to photographs of officers in full dress and soldiers posing beside their tents, such as the Crimean War photographs taken by Fenton prior to Robertson and Beato's arrival. It was around this time that the partnership, Robertson & Beato, ended. Robertson remained in India while Beato moved on to China to document the end of the Opium Wars, ca. 1860. Here, he met sketch-artist, Charles Wirgman, and established a close friendship.
    Wirgman went to Japan and later convinced Beato to join him there. In 1863, the two shared a studio in Yokohama, and in 1865, they officially became partners as Beato and Wirgman, Artists and Photographers. During his career in Japan, Beato also traveled throughout the countryside recording the lifestyle of the times. In 1868, he published a two volume album culled from his travel and studio photographs: Photographic View of Japan with Historical and Descriptive Notes, Compiled from Authentic Sources, and Personal Observations During a Residence of Several Years. Volume One, Views of Japan, was comprised of individually tipped in sepia-toned albumen prints. Volume Two, Native Types, was of hand-colored albumen prints, probably hand-painted by Wirgman, also individually tipped in the album.
    Beato ended his career in both Japan and photography in ca. 1885 when he went to the Sudan to one last time photograph a war. Afterwards, he removed to Burma to sell native furniture and crafts in Rangoon. It is speculated that he died in 1907.
    The Beato photographs in the Department of Special Collections are comprised chiefly of two groups of photographs taken in China ca. 1858. They are mounted albumen prints, untitled, and probably were removed from either one or several photograph albums. Also in the collection is a hand-colored albumen print from Japan.
    - Behind a building, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Rear view of building, 3/4 hidden by a brick wall, shows ornate roof.
    - Building with three doors, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Close-up view reveals ornate detail on exterior of building.
    - Courtyard, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Low building with courtyard divided by fences with stone lions.
    - Man crossing bridge, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Small bridge crossing tree-lined stream in front of stick fence; slight tear on mount.
    - Market place[?], 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Crowd in front of building on river brank; large tear top of mat, slight tears bottom of photograph.
    - Pagoda [?] behind tree, 24 x 19 cm.; mounted: 53 x 36 cm.
      Close-up partial view of building.
    - Pagoda, 19 x 23 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Photograph, taken from ground angle, shows different levels of the building.
    - Rock garden, 1863; 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Man standing behind fence in foreground; "1863" embossed at top of photograph.
    - Rooftops and courtyard, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      View of tiled roofs, pagoda in distance, courtyard on left; tear on mount.
    - Rooftops and trees, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Close-up view of tiles roofs; pagoda in distance.
    - Rooftops, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      View of a lower class neighborhood in an unidentified city with a river in the distance; has minor abrasion.
    - Ruins, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      View looking up stone steps with overgrown foliage; water stains, abrasion on photograph.
    - Shrine [?], 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Close-up view shows portion of building with a double roof.
    - Two sleeping Japanese women, 20 x 27 cm.; mounted: 28 x 33 cm.; Hand-colored albumen print
    - Wall, 19 x 24 cm.; mounted: 36 x 53 cm.
      Low brick wall, pagoda on hill in distance.
  - Beaton, Cecil Walter Hardy: Gertrude Stein. n.p., ***, ca. 1930.; 1 item. 24.5 x 19.5 cm. Photograph. Mounted and overmatted: 43 x 35.5 cm.
  - Beauchy, E., 2 items. Photographs. (Box 44)
  - Bedow ***, 1 item. Photograph.
    - GAR, New Orleans, 1907; 19.5 x 25.5 cm.; Silver print 7½" x 9" signed; mounted and overmatted: 40.5 x 50.7 cm.
  - Bennett, G. Leonard ***, 1 item. Photograph.
    - Rural Stop, ca. 1946; # 1324; 14 x 16 ins.: 34.5 x 40 cm.; Blue toned silver print; Abrasion along lower center; buckling; worn and chipped edges; mounted and overmatted: 50.5 x 60.6 cm.
  - Bernard, Ruth, 2 photographs.
  - Bing, Ilse, 2 photographs. (Box 15)
    Views of a French Chateau.
  - Blanco, Amanda, 6 items. Photographs.
    1 item - box 45.
    Amanda Blanco is a local Southern California photographer currently living in the Venice area. The photographs in this collection are primarily of people in the book world: authors, booksellers, book collectors, etc. For the most part, photographs are untitled and signed in pencil in the lower right-hand margin of the image. Measurements of the images include the margins.
    - Robert Nathan, 1979; 37.7 x 35.6 cm.; mounted and overmatted: 40.5 x 50.7 cm.
      Portrait of the author seated outdoors next to a hedge.
    - Jack Smith and his airdale, 1980; 35 x 27.2 cm.; mounted and overmatted: 40.5 x 35.5 cm.
    - Dr. Franklin Murphy seated in his Times-Mirror Building office, 1979; 35.7 x 27.8 cm.; mounted and overmatted: 50.5 x 40.5 cm.
    - Jake Zeitlin, 1978; 37.5 x 37.8 cm.
      Two-thirds profile of the emminent Los Angeles bookseller holding an antiquarian book.
    - Norman Corwin, 1980; 27.5 x 35.6 cm.
      Profile portrait.
    - "Doris Harris, owner Doris Harris Autographs", 1979; 20 x 25.3 cm.; Signed in ink on verso.
      Portrait of local manuscripts dealer in her shop leafing through a folder of manuscripts.
  - Bonfils, Felix, 41 items. Photographs.
    39 items - box 37.
  - Bourne, Samuel **, 30 items. Photographs.
  - Briquet, A., 37 items. Photographs. (Box 109)
  - Brogi, Giacomo, 13 items. Photographs. (Box 46)
  - Bullock, Wynn: A collection of photographs of Henry Miller at Big Sur and vicinity., 21 photographs. (Box 47)
  - Burgess, Charles, 3 items. (Box 48)
  - Calder, Roland, 1 item. Photograph.
    - "Conference", ca. 1930; 5" x 7": 12.5 x 17.5 cm.; Silver print, signed; mounted and overmatted: 40.7 x 50.5 cm.
  - Cameron, Mrs. Julia Margaret (Pattie): Mrs. Cameron's photographs from the life. [v.p. (England),***, ca.1860s]; 38 items. Photographs and 1 holograph index. Mounted and overmatted, 48.5 x 38.5 cm.
    The photographs were part of an album with the above cover title. Three additional photographs laid in.
    A collection of matted photographs, at one time assembled in a bound volume, with the original leather label, "Mrs. Cameron's Photographs From The Life," and an inscription in Mrs. Cameron's hand, "A gift to Aubrey Ashwood Taylor from his earliest truest and fondest friend, Julia Margaret Cameron. 29 Sept. 1869." There is also a manuscript table of contents. Of the original 51 photographs, 20 are lacking. There are four photographs not called for in the table of contents, mounted on the versos of #s 6, 12, 25, 32. All appear to be photographs of Mrs. Cameron's daughter-in-law, Annie Cameron. The following is a list of the 31 photographs (not including the four of Annie Cameron) in the collection with the original table of contents numbers. These were identified with the help of Mr. Charles Mallard, 19th century art curator, L.A. County Museum. A few are in question.
    2. Christabel, study from May Prinsep.
    3. Beatrice, study from May Prinsep, eyes down.
    4. Beatrice, studey from may Prinsep, eyes open.
    5. Mary Mother (Mary of Freshwater)
    6. The Mountain Nymph.
    9. Sir J.W. Herschel taken at his residence Collingwood, April 1867.
    10. Little Margie (Thackeray) called the Christ-kind.
    11. Sappho (study of Mary of Freshwater)
    12. G.F. Watts, R.A.
    12 A. The Guardian Angel (Annie Cameron.)
    15. Alfred Tennyson, the last portrait of him, June 3rd, 1869, Freshwater.
    17. Herr Joachim, March 1868.
    18. Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882, taken at Freshwater, 1868.
    20. Mrs. Herbert Duckworth, taken at Saxonbury, 1868.
    21. Marie Spartali, Freshwater, 1868.
    24. Marie Spartali, Freshwater, 1868.
    25. W.E.H. Lecky, M.A., 1868.
    25 A. Verso. (Annie Cameron)
    26. The Echo. Freshwater, 1868. (Campbell, Hattie.)
    27. The Rosebud Garden of Girls. Portrait group of the sisters, Nelly Marie, Christins, Ethel, Fran Lyttel (?)
    29. Marie Spartali as "Imperial Eleanore."
    32. Professor Jowett. 1866. Taken at Freshwater.
    32 A. Verso. (Annie Cameron?)
    35. Queen Esther fainting before King Ahassuerus. Freshwater, 1864.
    38. Study of King David from Henry Taylor, 1865.
    40. Acting Grand Mama study for MayPrinsep.
    41. La Donna at her devotions. (Study from Marie Spartali)
    43. Paul and Virginia. Freshwater, 1864.
    45. The Flower Girl. Freshwater, 1868.
    46. The Dedication. Freshwater, 1868.
    47. La Madannoa Reposata. Freshwater, 1864.
    48. Lionel Tennyson in the character of Marquis de St. Cast as acted at our Private Theatricals. 1868.
    49. The Spirit of the Vine. Study from Marie Spartali, 1868.
    50. "The Beauty of Holiness." Freshwater, 1866.
    51. "Love" (out of a series of nine studies, The Fruits of the Spirit) Freshwater, 1864.
  - Cameron, Mrs. Julia Margaret (Pattie): Mrs. Cameron's photographs from the life. [v.p. (England),***, ca.1860s]; 2 items.
    Also shelved will collection (not part of album):
    - Photograph of Sir Coutts Lindsay, Bart. n.p. (Eng.), undated.
    - Photograph of Lord Alfred Tennyson. n.p. (Eng.), 1869 June 3; 2 copies.
  - Caponigro, Paul: Color nature landscapes I [pictures] / by Paul Caponigro ... [et al.] - New York: DEP Editions,***, [1983].; 1 portfolio: chibachrome prints; 58 x 75 cm. 10 images, various sizes, signed under the print. - All mounted and overmatted to either 71 x 56 cm. or 56 x 71 cm.
    #21 of an edition of 50.
  - Carroll, Lewis: Tennyson [picture] / Lewis Carroll. - London: Cundall, 1861.; 1 photograph: sepia, 11 x 6 cm. (Box 49)
    Carte-de-visite photograph taken by Lewis Carroll, Sept. 28, 1857.
    - Cf. Lewis Carroll, photographer / Helmut Gernsheim, 1950, plate 8.
  - Casserly, Alexander W., 21 items. Photographs. (Box 50)
  - Cates, Vincent ***, 2 items. Photographs.
    - Capit-l Reef-2, # 385; 14½ x 16½ ins.: 34.7 x 41.7 cm.; Silver print, unsigned; mounted and overmatted: 63.3 x 50.4 cm.
    - "Capitol Reef -2", ca. 1940.; 14" x 16": 34.5 x 42 cm.; Silver print, unsigned; mounted and overmatted: 50.3 x 63.2 cm.
  - Chapman, Wendell: Rocky Mountain Elk. [Yellowstone National Park,*, ca. 193-?]; 1 item. 27 x 35 cm. Original photograph. (Box 14)
  - Chase, H. L., 14 items.
  - Clark, Eli P.: On board the steamer Manchuria, [Hawaii, 1906]; 23 items. Photographs. (Box 51)
    Photographs taken by Eli P. Clark, or a member of his family, during a trip to Hawaii when their steamer ran aground off the coast. Clark was president and manager of the Pasadena and Los Angeles Interurban Railway and of the Los Angeles Pacific Railway.
  - Clarke, Charles G., 5 items. Photographs. (Box 52)
  - Coburn, Alvin Langdon, 2 items. Photographs. (Box 36)
  - Connell, Will **, 1 item. Photographs.
    The Grabhorn Brothers. 1929.
  - Cornell, Ralph Dalton**, 1 item. Photographs.
  - Cornell, Ralph Dalton: Harold Lloyd gardens. Los Angeles., ca. 192-.; 40 items. 10.5 x 8cm. Glass negatives. (Box 53)
    Archibald E. Hanson was the landscape gardener of the Lloyd estate. Mr. Cornell photographed the gardens. The series is numbered G-1 through G-42, 20 and 21 lacking.
    Modern contact prints are available.
  - Cornell, Ralph Dalton: Kerckhoff Hall, UCLA. Los Angeles., ca. 193-.; 8 items. 10 x 8 cm. Glass negatives.; Numbered 2-9.
    Allison and Allison were the architects.
  - Cornell, Ralph Dalton: Royce Hall, UCLA. Los Angeles., ca. 193-.; 10 items. 10 x 8 cm. Glass negatives.
  - Corot, Jean Baptiste Camille: Le songeur. [Arras, 1854]; 1 item. 14 x 19cm. Cliché-verre. Mounted and overmatted 20.3 x 25.4 cm.
    The glass plate was probably prepared and the print pulled by Adalbert Cuvelier.
    Robaut: 3164.
  - Corthell, Wendell G., 1 item. Photograph.
    - Venice, 1906; # 1328; 7 x 5 ins.: 17.1 x 12 cm.; Stain top right corner; slightly chipped corners.; mounted and overmatted: 50.5 x 40.5 cm.
  - Cunningham, Imogen, 5 items. Photographs.
    1 item - box 54.
    - Gertrude Stein. San Francisco, 1937; 23 x 19.5 cm.; mounted, 36.5 x 29 cm.; Signed on the mount. [overmatted by Special Collections]
      Printed by the Imogen Cunningham Trust under her supervision in 1976.
    - Robert Ignatius Burns. San Francisco, 1975; 19.5 x 16.5 cm.; mounted, 36.5 x 29 cm.; Signed on the mount.
    - Marianne Moore. San Francisco, 1957; 17.5 x 12.5 cm.; mounted, 35 x 27.5 cm.; Signed on the mount.
    - Josephine Miles. San Francisco, 1956; 14.5 x 12 cm.; mounted, 35 x 27.5 cm.; Signed on the mount.
    - Willend Lathrop. n.p., undated; 23.5 x 18.3 cm.; mounted, 27.5 x 21.5 cm.; On verso of mount: "Willend Lathrop - 'Cry.'"
  - Curtis, Edward Sheriff ***, 3 items. Photographs.
    - [Untitled] Portrait of Rabindranath Tagore. Seattle., 1930s; 20 x 15 cm.; mounted: 30 x 24 cm. Signed on the mount.
    - "Herding sheep -Navajo", ca. 1904; Platinum print, signed.; 27.8 x 39.3 cm.; mounted and overmatted: 40.6 x 50.7 cm.
    - [Untitled] Portrait of bride and groom. Los Angeles, ca. 1940s; Silver print, signed.; 23.8 x 18.4 cm.; mounted and overmatted: 50.5 x 40.5 cm.
  - Darnley, Sandra K. *, 2 items. (Box 25)
    Los Angeles photographer.
  - Dickson, M., 2 items. (Box 55)
  - Dixon, Joseph: Deer. [n.p.] *, 1927.; 1 item. 41 x 32cm. Original photograph. (Box 24)
  - Doolittle, James N. **, 22 items. Photographs.; 2 photographs are double-sided.
  - Dufty, F. K., [ca. 1871-1874]; 9 items. Photographs. (Box 56)
    ["Cartes de visite" or "ethnographic" photographs depicting natives of Fiji. Includes two photographs of Fijian King Ratu Seru Cakobau.]
    [Photocopies of the photographs are in the Collection File.]
  - Fein, Philip: Architectural photographs. San Francisco, 1950-1958.; 3 boxes. 8 x 10 photographs, 4 x 5 negs. (Box 113, Box 114, Box 115)
    This is a collection of architectural photographs of San Francisco and the surrounding areas, circa 1950-1958.
    - East Bay Franklin Tel Building, by Thomsen & Wilson, San Francisco., 16 photographs. (Neg. #C991 4 x 5, 3 5 x 7 color) (Box 113)
    - Sailors Union of the Pacific, by Wm. Gladstone Merchant, San Francisco., 15 photographs. (Neg. # D87: 15 4 x 5, 4 5 x 7) (Box 113)
    - Berkeley High School Auditorium, by Gutterson, San Francisco., 1950.; 12 photographs. (Neg. #D315: 25) (Box 113)
    - Frances Elkins, decorator, v.p., 1951.; 32 photographs. (Neg. #E39: 32 4 x 5, 14 4 x 5 color) (Box 113)
    - Leo J. Meyberg Bldg., by Ward & Bolles, San Francisco., 1951.; 9 photographs. (Neg. # E92: 19) (Box 113)
    - Paula Schoenholz house, Mill Valley, by Appleton & Walford, San Francisco., 1951.; 6 photographs. (Neg. #E169: 6) (Box 113)
    - Parkside Library, San Francisco, by Appleton & Walford., 1951.; 5 photographs. (Neg. #E179: 8) (Box 113)
    - Sam Bloom house, by Stauffacher, Jr., 1953.; 11 photographs. (Neg. #G99: 14) (Box 113)
    - Palo Alto City Hall, by Leslie Nichols., 1953.; 23 photographs. (Neg. #G107: 20) (Box 113)
    - Burton School, by John Lyon Reid, San Francisco., 15 photographs. (Neg. #H227: 14) (Box 113)
    - General Petroleum Corp., San Mateo, by R.M. Garrick, Los Angeles., 1954.; 18 photographs. (Neg. #H240: 23) (Box 113)
    - Dr. Weinstein's office, San Francisco, by Hertzska & Knowles, San Francisco., 1958.; 18 photographs. (Neg. #J9: 7) (Box 113)